schott.com 2018-03-02

# SCHOTT Group - Privacy Statement | EN | SCHOTT AG

## 1\. General

SCHOTT AG, as well as the other companies in the SCHOTT Group, intend to give you as much control over your personal data as possible.

As a rule, you can access SCHOTT websites without actively disclosing any of your personal details.  However, in several areas of the SCHOTT websites, you are requested to enter personal details, with which we can make the website more useful for you and help us to remain in contact with you.

You are requested to provide such data, for example, when you subscribe to a newsletter, if you request information material, if you send us suggestions with our contact forms or if you participate in an online survey. If you ask us not to use these data for making further contact, we will respect your request, also if you unsubscribe as a recipient of newsletters.

The personal data provided for the purposes described above will be treated confidentially and will exclusively be stored and used within the context of the relationship between you and SCHOTT AG.  The data provided to us shall not be sent to any external third parties or organisations outside of the SCHOTT Group.  Your data are only sent to companies in the SCHOTT Group, if you contact them directly, have consented or if it is necessary to implement the offer or services, which you intend to use.

## 2\. Storage of access data

With each access by a user on a page from the SCHOTT AG online content as well as with each file download, the access data referring to this procedure will be stored in a log file on our server.

Every data record comprises:

  * the page from where the file was downloaded;
  * the file name;
  * the download date and time;
  * the access status (file transmitted, file not found, etc.);
  * a description of the type of web browser used;
  * the client's IP address

In regards to the geographic location of the user, an estimate based on the IP number will be made, which will subsequently be evaluated for statistics.

Accrued user and connection data will be analyzed only for trends and statistics and evaluated anonymously solely for the purpose of optimizing our Internet presence. 

There will be no disclosure of data to third parties for any commercial or non-commercial purposes. 

The user is entitled to obtain free information on any stored personal data relating to him/her upon request. In addition, the user has the right to correction, blockage and deletion of such personal data as provided for by law.

## 3\. Cookies

Cookies are small text files transmitted from the Internet to your computer together with the presently accessed data. These data will be stored on your computer and held ready for future access.

We use cookies in some areas. On linked pages cookies may also be used without any possibility on our part to advise you about this.

####  3.1 Session cookies

Particularly within the context of logging in, so-called session cookies are required, as we need these data for authentication and for controlling access to the various areas of our portal for reasons of user friendliness. The validity of the session cookies is limited to the duration of your visit to our portal. They are automatically deleted when the browser is closed. This information is not with linked with personal data.

####  3.2 Statistics tracking

These cookies enable us to analyse the website use in an anonymised form and the data protection regulations accordingly. We evaluate the data as trends and in the form of statistics, in order to optimise the experience of visitors to our website.

####  3.3 Permanent cookies

These types of cookies are stored on your device for a specific time period, however, no longer than for 10 year and are not even deleted when the browser is closed. Permanent cookies are used a such points which we need to remember over and above your browser sessions, in order to save your preferences, so that they can be retrieved for the next visit to a site.

#### 3.4 Remarketing

SCHOTT uses the remarketing function of Google Inc. ("Google") on this website.

With this function, SCHOTT can address you by placing personalised, interest-related advertisements for offers of SCHOTT, while you are visiting other websites in the Google display network. In order to perform the necessary analyses of website use, so-called cookies are used (see above). These are used to record and send to Google, your visits to the website, as well as anonymised data about the use of the website.  Your personal data are not stored. If you visit another website in the Google Display Network after this, advertisements will be displayed to you, which are highly likely to take account of, or refer to, product and information areas, which you have previously retrieved.

You can permanently deactivate the use of these cookies for all websites by following the link below and downloading and installing the plug-in, which is available there: <https://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin>. Alternatively, you can deactivate the use of cookies by third party providers by opening the deactivation site of the Network Advertising Initiative (at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>) and implementing the further information referred to there for the opt-out.

#### 3.5 Google Analytics

Parts of this website also uses Google Analytics for statistics tracking, a web analysis service of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States ( **„Google“** ).

Google will analyze your use of our website on our behalf. To this purpose, we use, among others, Cookies as described above. The information collected by Google in connection with your use of our website (e.g. the referring website, which of our webpages you visit, your browser type, your language settings, your operating system, your screen resolution) will be transmitted to a server of Google in the US, where it will be stored and analyzed; the respective results will then be made available to us in an anonymized form. In addition, portions of this page use the Google Analytics demographics reports, which use Google's interest-based advertising data and third-party visitor data (such as age, gender, and interests). This data is not attributable to any particular person and can be disabled at any time through the [ad settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).

The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. However, we use the function “ __anonymizeIp()_ “ which truncates IP addresses within the area of Member States of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area in order to rule out any connection between this data and a person. Only in exceptional cases, the whole IP address will be first transferred to a Google server in the USA and truncated there. Moreover, Google is certified under the [EU-US Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI), which ensures an adequate level of data protection with respect to the processing of data by Google in the US.

You can turn off Google Analytics for future visits of the website www.schott.com. Therefore, please deactivate the check box next to section 3.2 Statistics tracking and click “save”. Alternatively, you can also opt-out from being tracked by Google Analytics with effect for the future by downloading and installing a [Google Browser Plugin](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

You may also refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. However, please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website.

For further information on Google Analytics, please refer to the [Google Analytics Terms of Service](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html), the [Google Analytics security and privacy principles](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en), and the [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en-GB/policies/privacy/).

## 4\. Links to other websites

Our online contents include links to other websites. Although we select links very carefully, we do not have any influence on the contents of linked pages or on compliance with privacy policies of the operators of other websites. As a provider, SCHOTT is responsible for its own contents in accordance with general regulations. 

"Links" to contents offered by other providers are potentially to be differentiated from such SCHOTT’s own contents. SCHOTT will not assume any liability for, nor adopt any third-party contents which are provided for use through links and are particularly identified. Illegal, erroneous or incomplete contents, as well as damage resulting from the use or failure to use such information are the exclusive responsibility of the provider of the website to which reference was made. Our editorial team shall only be responsible for third-party references if they have positive knowledge of them, including any potential illegal or criminal contents, and if it would technically be feasible and reasonable to prevent their use.

## 5\. Business relationships

Information published by SCHOTT on its own sites may contain references to products and services possibly not announced or available in your country. Such information does not imply SCHOTT's intention to offer the said products and services in your country. Please contact our regional distributor or representative, as the case may be, who will gladly inform you as to the availability of such products and services.

The SCHOTT websites use brand names to which either SCHOTT or third parties have proprietary rights. Such brand names must not be used without the consent of the relevant holders of rights. SCHOTT holds all rights to the information and the design of its websites and reserves such rights. The responsible processing of your data as well as compliance with all applicable national and international privacy policies is a matter of fact for SCHOTT.

## 6\. Information on data security

SCHOTT is aware of how important the discreet treatment and protection of information transmitted by you via the Internet is. Data security on e-commerce sites is given absolute priority. We have therefore made great effort to ensure that our online security measures are effective. SCHOTT shop sites are encrypted with SSL technology. 

SCHOTT websites requiring the input of commercially relevant data, such as a credit card number, are transmitted with SSL encryption. SCHOTT endeavors to continuously adjust encryption technology along with technological progress in order to ensure the confidentiality of data transmitted via the Internet. 

Should you have any queries or comments regarding our privacy policy, please contact us via [E-mail](mailto:info.datenschutz@schott.com).

## 7\. Register of Proceedings of the Corporate Data Privacy Officer

## Public register of proceedings regarding the processing of personal data

The German Federal Data Protection Act (Bundesdatenschutzgesetz (BDSG)) stipulates in Section 4g that the data protection officer is to provide information to the public pursuant to Section 4e BDSG in a suitable manner upon request. The following summary provides an overview of the relevant information. 

## 7.1 Name of responsible post SCHOTT AG

## 7.2 Executive Board members

Dr. Frank Heinricht (Chairman)  
Hermann Ditz  
Dr. Heinz Kaiser  
Dr. Jens Schulte

Authorized Corporate Data Privacy Officer:  
Dr. Roland Leroux

## 7.3 Adress of the responsible post

SCHOTT AG  
Hattenbergstrasse 10  
55122 Mainz  
Germany  

## 7.4 Purpose of data collection, processing or use

SCHOTT is an international technology group that has been developing and producing specialty glass, specialty materials, components and systems for more than 125 years with the goal of improving people's living and working conditions.  
The following industries are our main markets: household appliances, pharmaceutics, solar energy, electronics, optical systems, construction and automotive. SCHOTT’s well-known brands are e.g. CERAN®, ROBAX®, ZERODUR®, FIOLAX®, and PYRAN®.  
The SCHOTT group of companies has production and distribution facilities in 35 countries.  
Data collection, processing and use serve to achieve the above-mentioned goals. The main areas for the processing of personal data are: 

  * Personnel (administration and development)
  * Suppliers (administration)
  * Customers (administration and customer care)
  * Business management processes (administration and production)

## 7.5 Description of the individuals concerned and of related data and data categories

Customer data, employee data and supplier data, to the extent required for achievement of the goals mentioned in 4. above.

## 7.6 Recipients or recipient categories to whom/ to which data may be disclosed

Public offices in case of mandatory legal regulations, external contractors in accordance with Section 11 BDSG, as well as external offices and departments of SCHOTT AG for achieving the goals mentioned in 4. above.

## 7.7 Statutory periods for data retention

The data are deleted upon expiry of the legal, statutory or contractually agreed retention periods. Data to which these retention periods do not apply are deleted once the goals stated in 4. above are no longer applicable. 

## 7.8 Projected data transmission to other countries

In order to process procedures within the scope of the business purpose, data are transmitted to authorities, customers and suppliers in different countries in accordance with the above-mentioned international guidelines. 

## 7.9 Security measures

SCHOTT AG ensures compliance with safety measures pursuant to Section 9 BDSG through care in order placement, appropriate quality specifications and employee training. 

SCHOTT AG  
Corporate Data Privacy Officer

If you have any questions regarding our data protection procedures, please do not hesitate to contact us at: [info.datenschutz@schott.com](mailto:info.datenschutz@schott.com).
